Ekene D. Onoh

Fontana, CA • (909) 301-1894 • ekene.onoh123@gmail.com • ekeneonoh456.github.io

PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

As organizations around the globe become more dependent on technology, the need for technically skilled
individuals who can aid these companies becomes more blatant. While I possess programming, networking,
analytical, and problem-solving skills along with experience in cybersecurity and software engineering, my
ability to lead, remain optimistic, learn fast, and cooperate with others allows me to be a morale boost and a
solid contributor to any team in the IT industry.

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA Security+ CE
 - Credential ID: VNKGMQEV17K6V5GZ
- CompTIA Network+ CE
 - o Credential ID: CD4CZS0YN2RE1Y35
- Google Cybersecurity
 - o Credential ID: 8WTT5BE69DNC

EXPERIENCE

• Cyber Security Researcher (2023)

Apollo Information Systems

- Internship working with AIS where I was tasked with researching modern hacking tools, collecting
 data about companies that have been attacked, and assisting companies with improving web
 security.
- Software Engineer (2022)

Tata Consultancy Services

- Internship with TCS where our team developed a full stack web application that was a live chat program for customer support.
- Web & App Development (2023-2024)

Built Portfolio Website

- o ekeneonoh456.github.io
- Created a website that holds my professional portfolio and experience using HTML, CSS,
 JavaScript, and Google Apps Script. It is currently being hosted using Github Pages.

Bowie State University Shuttle App

- A part of a team that built an app for our school's shuttle service.
- Network Administration (2024)
 - o Project where I created VMs to simulate network environments.
 - Created Active Directory Domain where I created users and groups and configured permissions.
 - Coded PowerShell scripts to automate various tasks within Active Directory.
- Hackathons & Competitions (2022-Present)
 - NCAE Cyber Games Spring 2022, NCCDC Hivestorm Fall 2022, National Cyber League (NCL), AWS HBCU 2022 Business Case Competition, MorganHacks 2023, UMD BitCamp 2023
- Math Tutor and Teacher Assistant (2020-2023)

Bowie State University

- Worked as a math tutor and teacher assistant assisting and teaching students in a wide range of college math courses.
- Treasurer (2021-2023)

BSU Disciples, BSU Circle K International, and BSU Honors Student Organization

Managing the budgets and financial records for multiple organizations. BSU Disciples is a Bible

study/support group, BSU Circle K International is a community service organization, and BSU Honors Student Organization is the school's Honors Program.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Understanding of C, C++, Linux Shell programming, Git, and GitHub.
- Security and networking fundamentals required for CompTIA Security+ CE and Network+ CE
- Experience with Active Directory, Powershell, Shodan, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
 Native, Expo, Springboot, Angular, RabbitMQ, Maven, Postman, SQL, AWS, CockroachDB, and VHDL.
- Ability to manage and analyze data and databases.
- Remain calm and optimistic during stressful and serious situations.
- While I am a detailed and precise problem solver, I am always open to all ideas regarding problem-solving with a team.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Bowie State University, Bowie, MD
- Etiwanda High School, Rancho Cucamonga, CA

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Bowie State University Honors Program
- Dean's List at Bowie State University (3.8 GPA)
- National Society of Leadership and Success Member (NSLS)